Jonah Rosenblum

Computer Science and Engineering University of Michigan

jonaher@umich.edu jonahrosenblum.com

Research Interests

I am interested in building zero-trust systems that protect data privacy and integrity. My recent works use trusted hardware technology to protect the sensitive data in genome analytics, prevent Rowhammer attacks between VMs via architecture-aware memory allocation, and provide scalable freshness protections via novel trusted memory design. Our new research focuses on extending trusted hardware to ML accelerators and intelligent "time locked" disks that are immutable for set periods of time to prevent ransomware.

Education

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2022-Current

Advisor: Satish Narayanasamy

GPA: 3.99

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI

M.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

Jan 2021-Dec 2021

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI

B.S. in Computer Science

Sep 2017-Dec 2020

GPA: 3.83

Publications

- 1. **Jonah Rosenblum**, Juechu Dong, Satish Narayanasamy. "SECRET-GWAS: Confidential Computing for Population-Scale GWAS." Under submission in Nature Methods.
- 2. Kevin Loughlin, **Jonah Rosenblum**, Stefan Saroiu, Alec Wolman, Dimitrios Skarlatos, and Baris Kasikci. "Siloz: Leveraging DRAM Isolation Domains to Prevent Inter-VM Rowhammer." In **Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP)**. 2023.

Employment

Google Virtual

Software Engineering Intern

May-August 2021

Team: GCloud Infrastructure

Analyzed inversion between network and application priority for high-priority Google traffic across all clusters and identified strategies to align less latency sensitive traffic with appropriate QoS.

Google Virtual

Software Engineering Intern

Team: Cloud Trace

May-August 2020

Worked on open-source telemetry tool OpenTelemetry, implementing graceful shutdown for processes to ensure all traces and metrics are exported.

Teaching

Advanced Operating Systems (EECS 582)

Ann Arbor, MI

Graduate Student Instructor for Prof. Ryan Huang.

Sep-Dec 2023

Parallel Computer Architecture (EECS 570)

Ann Arbor, MI

Graduate Student Instructor for Prof. Satish Narayanasamy.

Jan-May 2021

(Overall, Jonah Rosenblum was effective Q776) - 4.8/5 (5: Strongly Agree; 1 Strong Disagree)

Professional Activities

CSEG Security Reading Group Co-Chair

Ann Arbor, MI

Run weekly security group meetings to discuss current research papers.

Jan 2023-Current

Student Applicant Support Program Volunteer

Ann Arbor, MI

Provide prospective Ph.D. students with advice and feedback on applications.

Oct 2023-Current

Grad Mentor Program Volunteer

Ann Arbor, MI

Research/grad program mentor to Master's and Ph.D. students.

Sep 2023-Current

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Proficient in C, C++, and Python. Familiar with many other object-oriented languages.

Other skills: Kernel development (QEMU/Linux)